哦!
oh!
哇靠!
oh, man!
操
fuck.
- 然后呢? - 一枪爆头
- what's next? - one to the head.
绝不手软
i keep it quick.
没那么简单 臭小子
not yet, motherfucker.
你当真枪跟这彩弹那么简单
you shoot live  rounds like paint,
小心死都不知怎么死的
boy, you'll be the shit, you hear?
这跟真格洛克枪不是差不多嘛
yo, but these really do look like glocks.
嗯 故意做成那样子
yeah, they make them look that way.
说 干嘛瞄低?
yo, why you shoot low?
如果站得近 就一枪爆头
all right, if you're close, aim for the head.
远的话 记住对手可能穿反弹背心
if not, think vest.
你教我们的
that's the way you said it.
不错 有记性
a'ight. boy's learning.
火线重案组 第四季 第12集
the.wire.s04e12
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
*way down in the hole *
"这事儿就这样了?" -Bubbles
这间也想进?
you going inside this one too?
整栋楼都要搜
i'm gonna do  the whole block.
你撬了一间屋子啪地扔具尸体给我们 已经够糟了
it's bad enough you popped the top off one house and give us a body.
还想怎么着?
what the fuck do you think you're doing now?
- 做个实验 - 实验?
- an experiment. - an experiment?
哇操
oh, fuck me.
我这是跟居里夫人说话呢
i'm dealing with madam curie here.
这颗钉子来自一把汽钉枪
this nail here comes from a nail gun,
是从藏有尸体的屋子上拔下来的
and it comes from the house with a dead man inside.
其他屋子用的都是房管局的螺丝钉
every other house has screws that h.c.d. uses.
这城里只要是带这种钉子的三合板
we find these in the plywood anywhere in this city,
那后面就一定藏着尸体
and there's a body inside.
哟 干得不错啊
gosh, that's good work.
真的 我挺佩服的
no, i'm very impressed.
你当我木工啊?
do you see a tool belt on me?
你觉得我看起来像是五街开杂货店的白痴?
do i look like one of those fucking jerkoffs in aisle five of the home fuckin' depot?
今年还剩三周了
there's three weeks  left in the year,
咱组的破案率才不到50%
and our unit clearance rate is under 50%.
我们才不去找什么尸体咧
we do not go looking for bodies,
还他妈是腐烂的无名氏
especially moldering fucking john does.
我们干啥要活活把自己钉在靶心上啊
we do not put red up on the board voluntarily.
Jay 这么多尸体就在屋子里
jay, the bodies are in the houses,
Marlo Stanfield搞出来的尸体
marlo stanfield's bodies.
那是他的事儿
then they belong to him.
我知道你已不在我小队上了 "重案组"先生
now i realize you're no longer in my squad, mr. major crimes,
但你还是刑事调查局的人
but you're still part of c.i.d., right?
看看 我也还是个警长吧?
and look, i'm still a sergeant, right?
这是我的命令 Lester
and i'm giving you an order on this, lester.
除非是上头交代下来
until i feel chain-of -command down on this
有其他处理意见 否则你决不允许--
and until you hear otherwise, you will not--
我重申 决不允许再他妈拆...
i repeat not-- pull down any more...
任何木板
fucking wood!
走吧 伙计
let's go, man.
我早就估摸着学校预算
i mean, you know, i expect a shortfall
会有缺口 这也正常
when i look at the school budget. it's a natural.
可怎么能一欠就欠了5千4百万呢
but how in christ's name do you lose $54 million?
积少成多呗
one million at a time.
是啊 这也不是一日之寒
exactly. it didn't happen this morning.
这是Royce鼻子底下发生的事儿
this was on royce's watch.
市议会审查的时候就一点没个数儿?
you didn't get a whiff of this during council review?
这事儿既不能怪Royce也不能怪市议会
you can't blame the council or royce for the school budget.
学校的财政收支归学校董事会自己管
the fiscal responsibility is with the school board itself.
但市议会有监管责任啊
but the council does have oversight.
别想把屎盆子往我头上扣
don't even pretend to put this shit on me.
我们的预算报告上只显示市里拨的钱
only the city share shows  up on our budget review.
国家的钱我们见都没见过
we never see the state money.
你自己跟参谋长说 北大街上那些事儿
you'd better tell your pretty new chief of staff that whatever happens up on north avenue
得怪在学校头上
is on the school system.
这是把问题简单化了
that's a simplistic view, i think.
还能怎么复杂化呢?
how would you complicate it?
作为校董事会负责人  我必须指出这是簿记问题
as president of the school board, i'll argue this is a bookkeeping issue.
我们从99年起就债上滚债
we've simply been rolling the system's debt over since '99.
就这么滚啊滚到现在两手空空
you rolled it and rolled it until it ran out of cash.
这叫什么簿记 简直是无知
that's not bookkeeping,  that's stupidity.
到底是什么造成的呢 浪费?
so what are we talking  about here, waste?
腐败 贪污
fraud: embezzlement:
要我说虽然学校的财务系统一团糟
i would say that although the system has some poor accounting practices,
但到头会发现来大部分的钱
in the end we're going to find that most of the money
还是正常用在开课上的
was properly spent on programming.
行了行了 明白了
okay okay okay. we get it.
谁都没错
no one's responsible,
校董会没错 北大街的人没错  Clarence Royce没错
not the school board, not anybody on north avenue, not clarence royce,
市政厅没错 这里谁都没错行了吧
not the city council, no one at this table. fine.
那接下来怎么办?
so what's our next move?
增加物业税
bump the property tax rate:
削减开支
scale back our budget.
停止加薪 不招新员工 减少服务
no pay hikes, hiring freezes, reduced services,
让大家 学校 警察 火警 社工
tell everyone-- schools, police, fire, public works--
都勒紧裤带熬一两年
they have to hold the line for a year or two.
怎么搞
how:
我刚发起了整治街道行动
i just ran a clean-up- the-streets campaign.
在全城警察面前吹得花好稻好
i just got done promising the world to every cop in the city.
Annapolis (马里兰州府所在地)
annapolis.
你得好好拍拍他的共和党马屁
you go beg his republican ass.
"奶酪"一个人
the cheese stands alone.
这是在接头?
this the drop:
希望不是 他们还没出声儿呢
i hope not, 'cause they ain't called yet.
让我替Joe觉得挺过意不去的
make me feel bad  toward old prop joe.
转过去看看什么情况
yeah, go around where we can see y'all.
咱们开路开路的 Ronaldo
vamonos, 'naldo.
接头接得不错 够隐蔽
nice hookup. private.
兄弟们都挺赤胆忠心啊
damn, y'all some semper fi motherfuckers, ain't ya?
"奶酪"该招谁呢?
where cheese go to enlist?
这是先前欠Joe的25包货
that's 25 back to joe from what we was short before,
还有150包我们订了六点送到
and another 1 50 to up our order to six.
喂 说好四点的
whoa, we had you down for four.
我都不知道其他的地方的货能不能到
i don't know if we got extras coming off the boat.
那就先欠着别人的呗
short someone else then.
那看Joe怎么说吧
i'll see what joe says.
好
yeah.
等补货时间订了 我们给你打这个
when we set with the re-up,  we'll hit you on that.
半小时后到你们说的地方取东西
the shit will be where you told us half hour later.
- 我们已经不用这个了 - 我们也不用
- yo, we ain't using these no more. - us neither.
到时我们就用临时电话打给你
what we do is ring you from a 958 exchange,
你们别接
east side, don't need to answer.
电话扔了 去碰面地点就行
just toss it, go to the meet.
哥几个后会有期
see you when i see you.
钞票扔出来 海洛因就到
money on the table,  "hairon" to follow.
在这儿盯着Marlo?
stay here on marlo?
不 我们跟踪"奶酪"
nah, we gonna stay with cheese.
探员 帮我开下门成不?
detective, would you get the door for me?
好事来了真是挡也挡不住啊
sometimes life just gives you a moment, huh?
这家伙本想黑我 结果反被黑了?
he was gonna do me, and instead he gets done?
我都走投无路了
i'm dipped in shit here.
我真他妈是全世界最幸运的人
i'm the luckiest motherfucker you know.
先生们
gentlemen,
目标还是Stanfield
the target is still mr. stanfield,
从案情进展来看
and from the look of things,
和俩月前我离开时比 基本还是原地踏步
we're no closer to him than when i left here two months ago.
他们就算不让我调查谋杀案
now they might not let me go after murders,
可阻止不了我查毒品
but they cannot stop me from chasing the drugs.
Leander 你帮我监听这帮人
leander, i want you surveilling his people.
看他们还用不用手机联络
see if they're still up on cell phones.
你查文件痕迹怎么样?
how are you with the paper trail?
- 好 - 我要你去市评估办公室
- okay. - i want you down at the city assessment office
把所有西区超过10万的购买记录调出来
pulling paper on all the purchases on the west side over $100,000.
拿去交管局查他名下所有豪华汽车
then get down to m.v.a. and check iuxury cars in his name, all right?
这小子干这行有段时间了
now this boy has been in the game for a while now.
很可能会想法洗钱
he might try to launder money.
Herc你去填表格 把能用的监听设备都征起来
herc, i want you on the paperwork, re-requisitioning the wiretap equipment
包括Marimow运去设备科的那批
that marimow shipped  on down to l.s.d.
全部都要用作后备 明白?
we're gonna need all of that to get backup, okay?
有人找我 我在失踪人口部 好吧
if anyone needs me, i'm down at missing persons, all right?
走吧
let's go.
- Lester? - 怎么
- lester? - yes?
- 你说得都挺好... - 嗯
- all this is cool... - mm-hmm.
可能不能当这些命令是以我的名义发出的?
...but you think we can do it so that the direction comes from me?
毕竟 这里我是警司嘛
i mean, i am the sergeant here.
Donut 你觉得这样如何?
donut, you think  this look right?
你干嘛编起来?
why you knock 'em down?
这样条子没那么容易认出我
so the police won't  scope me so easy.
可现在他们会说
but now all they gotta do is be like,
"喂 快去抓住那个编辫子的小黑鬼"
"yeah, go over there and just grab that little nigger with the braids."
妈的 怎么迟到那么久
damn, boy, you later than a motherfucker.
坐这儿眼睁睁地看着金主走过
been sitting out here watching money walk away.
你今天好休假了
you about to have the day off.
包裹给偷了
package was stolen, na'.
啥 从你家地下室?
what? out the back of your basement?
他们踢开门冲了进来 就这么着
they kicked my motherfucking door in. that's how they do.
警察怎么会知道你身上有货?
well, look, how the police know where you even be keeping your stash at?
有人告密呗 否则怎么会知道
some snitch-ass bitch, that's how they know.
看我不揪出他
i'ma find his ass too.
行了 我撤了
all right, man, i'm out.
我搞不懂你怎么就不吃猪肉了呢
i never did understand why you stopped eating the pig.
我从1974年就没在Polack Johnny吃过东西
i ain't been in a polack johnny's since 1974,
你知道什么对你好--
and if you knew what was good for you--
我知道什么好 你以前不也知道么
look, i know what's good. i remember when you did too.
想不到你竟然跟我搞起穆斯林这套了
i never saw you going all muslim on me.
不是这回事儿 我真相信
ain't that, but i do believe
至少在吃猪肉上 别的宗教比我们看得透彻
that other faiths have got the pig figured better than us a.m.e.s.
看到没?
see that?
你要是寻死 我总得劝你几句
if you checking out, i might feel the need to say a few words.
别 别跟我说这套
nah, i ain't got nothing to do with that.
我爱汉堡 就是吃完嘴里会一股子味儿
i love my pjs, but they do repeat on me.
你吃的时候该配原味酱
as memory serves, you got to  go with the original sauce,
哪有像你这样配泡菜辣酱的
not the kraut and chili like you do.
我烧心的事儿跟酸菜没关系
my pain ain't about no sauerkraut.
"上头"已经准备砍掉任何
"the puzzle palace" is ready to clip any program
不按州考制度来的课程
that ain't tied to the statewide tests.
问题是 我们的项目刚开始有点进展
the thing is, we're just starting to make a little headway in what we're doing.
你跟上头说过了?
you take it upstairs?
嗯 我跟老师一路找到了教育局负责人
yeah, me and the professor went all the way to go see the school superintendent.
结果呢?
and?
你没看报纸么?
you read the papers?
他们自己都忙着收拾预算烂摊子
they're a little busy ducking that budget mess.
五千万的缺口呢
$50 million in the hole,
哪敢再往新市长面前扔烫山芋
and they're scared to take any more problems to the new mayor.
- 你这项目是烫山芋么? - 那看你怎么看了
- is your thing a problem? - depends on how you look at it.
有些和稀泥的说起来我们只不过
a cover-your-ass type of person might say we're just
把跟不上普通班的学生揪出来
tracking any students that can't hack in the regular classes,
给他们点事做又不会拉低州统考分数
giving them work that don't show up on no statewide tests.
市政府说行 我们才能继续
city hall says it's okay, they keep our program.
不行我们就只能滚回大街了
if not, we on the street.
Odell Watkins
odell watkins.
我猜你也会想到他
i was hoping you'd say that name.
嗯 Carcetti听他的
yeah, he got carcetti's ear.
只要说服他 就能说服市府
if we sell him, maybe we sell the hall.
跟着那偷你东西的黑鬼
stalk that nigger, man,  that stole your shit.
- 嗯 - 他一出现
- yeah. - soon as he nod out,
拿板砖给丫当头来一下子
bust him in the head with a brick or some shit.
不不 这我可干不了
nah nah. that ain't me.
那也得给他点颜色瞧瞧
you can always give him a hotshot then.
还记得小Bunk?
y'all recall junior bunk?
在他的货里掺了 叫什么来着
cutting his shit with, uh, what you call it?
从殡仪馆偷的
stole it from the funeral home.
哦 你是说甲醛啊
oh, you thinking formaldehyde.
就那玩意儿
that's the shit.
那小子挺能耐
nigger's got a taste  of that shit,
医院为他害的病人特地开了个病房
university started a "junior bunk" ward.
我那白痴表弟都中标两三回了
my cousin laid his ignorant ass up there two, three times.
这么说这药力也没个准
ain't no guarantee in that, though.
那就用老鼠药呗
use some rat poison then.
不行 那东西烧起来不一样
no, man, that stuff don't cook up right.
要用就用氰化钠
what you need to use is that sodium cyanide.
- 那东西看着烧着来跟真货没两样 - 哪儿能找到
- that shit looks and cooks just like the real thing. - where i find that?
试试铁路边上的铸币厂
try, uh, minter's over there by the tracks,
或者卖电镀板的五金店
or one of those metal shops where they do plating.
- 得用多少? - 要不了多少
- how much i need? - it ain't gonna take much.
一小瓶能把整个马厩的马都放倒
a vial of that shit'd kill every horse in this stable.
- 这么就行了? - 杀这种黑鬼算不上杀
- that's all there is to it? - it ain't no thing to kill a nigger
本来干的就是脑袋提裤带上的营生
who's already about  the business of killing himself.
连警察都懒得来管
and the police, they ain't gonna pay no never mind.
只要你自己受得了
you the one's got to live with it is all.
失踪男青年比我想象的要多
more young males than i'd have thought.
我看不会都闯世界去了吧
i don't suppose they all went off in search of adventure.
这些档案展开实际调查过么?
you get a chance to do any street work on these files?
有才怪 Lester
shit, no, lester.
失踪人口五年前砍到只剩一名警员
they cut missing persons to one detective five years ago.
我连登记归档都来不及
i barely keep up with the paperwork.
随意
feel free.
记得复印了把原件还来归档
just make copies and return the originals for the files.
归档...好吧
for the files... right.
妈的 小子
damn, son.
Kenard说条子拿的?
kenard said the police took it?
他说他们破门而入
he said they kicked his door in.
人倒一个不抓?
and they ain't lock no one up?
你见着那扇门没?
yo, you see that door?
门铰链坏了没?
were the hinges broke?
要是按他说的警察踢门进去...
i mean, if he said they  put the boot to it...
铰链准坏了
them hinges gotta be hanging free.
我逼问他了
i sweated him, yo.
他不像是在骗我
he wasn't trying to scheme me.
那小兔崽子准是把货私吞了
that little motherfucker took that shit for himself.
肯定的
bet it.
你该好好问问他
and now you gotta step to him,
看他到底说没说真话
put something real behind them words.
你那西班牙小子呢?
where your spanish boy at?
他盯着"奶酪" 我召集人马
he's down on point with cheese while i round up soldiers.
这儿不就有人马么
you got soldiers right here.
你那两千大洋够收买法官?
your 2255 must have pleased some judge, huh?
反正够放我回家的了呗
enough to get me home, didn't it?
我是说 我知道他们能干活
i'm just saying, butch, i know they soldiers, but i'm
但这次我想稍微低调点
thinking about being a little more subtle on this one.
明白吗 不想打草惊蛇
you feel me? so they don't see me coming.
不像你啊 找陌生人干活
it ain't like you to work with strangers.
我是欢迎多样性
i'm celebrating diversity.
现在开始也不晚嘛
i'm thinking now the time to start doing that.
怎么样啊 亲爱的?
oh-hoo! what up, shorty?
你好哇宝贝?
what's up, baby?
- 哟 光彩照人啊 - 还凑合吧
- damn, girl, you looking good. - i'm maintaining.
- 不错不错 - 你还行?
- shit, i know that's right. - you doing all right?
嗯
yeah.
久违 久违
long time, long time.
我听说这笔买卖有大钱赚?
i got your word. some real money  to be made on this one, huh?
还记得怎么干不?
you remember how to do this?
上手就想起来了吧
i reckon it'll come back to me.
明白我说的了吧 Butch--
see that's what i'm  talking about, butch--
- 低调 - 嗯
- subtle. - hmm.
先擦玻璃的 不会留印子
glasses first, so they don't spot.
是 夫人
yes, ma'am.
- 你好 - 你好 Prezbo老师
- hello. - ho, mr. prezbo.
- 请进 - 没关系
- come in, please. - oh, that's okay.
我就是回家路上顺便来下
i just wanted to stop by on my way home
送Randy下周的功课过来
and drop off randy's  work for next week.
希望这件事赶快结束
hopefully this thing will be over soon.
也许吧 但我们也在考虑
maybe so, but we're looking at the possibility
下学期送他去华盛顿BookerT学校
of moving him to booker t.  washington next semester.
希望事不至此
i hope that isn't necessary.
我也不想 总之 谢谢你送这来
i hope so too. anyway, thanks for bringing this.
我会努力让他跟上进度
i'll try to keep him up to speed.
- 坚持住 孩子 - 谢谢
- hang in there, kiddo. - thanks.
这电话会议够长的
long conference call.
我的表看都快一个钟头了
about an hour so far by my watch.
让我跟这儿坐冷板凳
got me out here riding the wood.
很不巧州长的电话会议比预计时间要久
unfortunately the governor's phone call has gone longer than anticipated.
要不要喝点什么 咖啡
can i get you anything? coffee?
我还有其他约会
look, i have other appointments.
应该不会太久了
it shouldn't be much longer.
看Metro报里Fisher的专栏
check out fisher's column in metro.
他说 州长认为 上引号
he says, the governor thinks, quote,
最近的财政危机反映出
"this latest fiscal emergency calls into question
巴尔的摩教育系统的运作情况
the baltimore school system's ability to manage itself
乃至全市总体运转的缺陷
as well as the local oversight of the system,"
下引号
unquote.
狗娘养的
motherfucker.
他在其他市面前拆我台
he's playing to the d.c. suburbs.
他看准你两年后奔着他的位子去
he sees you coming for him two years from now.
人也不是傻瓜
he ain't no fool.
电子设备申请单都在这儿了
there's all your electronic requisitions right there.
嗯
mm-hmm.
这是谁 警察?
what one's that, a cop?
不 他是个保安
nah, security guard.
我看他倒不像是Marlo杀的
i don't think he's one of marlo's, though.
警督
lieutenant.
谁能告诉我这是怎么回事?
will someone explain to me what the fuck the brass is doing?
先是把我踢到电话收接组
first i get bounced to telephone reporting,
今早又突然接到电话...
then i get a call this morning...
海滨小屋造得怎么样了
how's that beach house coming, huh?
快好了 就是需要好多木材--
it's almost done. i just need a load of lumber--
太好了 好极了
that's great, just great.
欢迎 欢迎回来
welcome. welcome back.
这他妈是谁啊?
who the fuck is that?
他啊 Hauk警司...
that, sergeant hauk...
是本局最有效率的督查
is one of the most effective supervisors in our police department.
抱歉 会议比我们预计的长了点
sorry. it's just taking a little longer than we expected.
应该快结束了
it shouldn't be much longer, though.
我明白你说的
i understand what you're saying.
有些孩子是该上高中了 可Duquan不行
some of those kids are ready for high school, but not duquan.
- 我... -...收养他了?
- i've... -...adopted him?
我这学期注意到Duquan了
i've noticed duquan this semester.
营养好了 衣服也干净了
he's more nourished, wears fresher clothes.
有时候身上还有香皂味
sometimes he even smells like soap.
你和你妻子
you and your wife,
还没生孩子吧?
you don't have children, do you?
- 还没 - 快生吧
- not yet, no. - well, have some.
生好生坏 那才是你自己的娃
for better or for worse, they're yours for life.
学校孩子毕竟不是你的
the kids in this school aren't yours.
你该尽的力尽了 就该放手
you do your piece with them,  and you let them go.
Duquan之后 还会有很多呢
because there'll be plenty more coming up behind duquan,
他们也需要你的帮助
and they're gonna need your help too.
你五分钟后不是要上第三节课么?
you've got your third period in five minutes, right?
安静 安静
settle down. settle down.
我们要集中精力对付考试
we need to concentrate on these tests.
操他娘的
aw, fuck this, man.
什么"要是Jane的爸爸给她一星期零用钱"
talking about, "lf jane's father gives jane one week's worth of allowance..."
我家里怎么不给我零用钱
shit, i ain't got no allowance where i stay at.
连爸爸都没有
no father, neither.
六边形有几条边 管我屁事儿啊?
how many sides a sexagon got? why i care about that?
要考试通过才能升到高年级啊
you need to take the test so you can move on to the next level.
都他妈傻逼 待哪儿不一样啊
i ain't moving nowhere but out this motherfucker.
- 就是 - 好了 安静下来
- hell, yeah. - all right. let's settle down.
从第一题开始
let's start with question number one.
安静
settle down!
够了 够了 听好了
all right. all right, listen up.
题目是
here's the problem:
两对夫妇走进一家餐厅
two couples go into a restaurant.
- 拿到的账单-- - 他们说"夫妇"
- they get the check-- - yo, when they say "couples,"
- 是说已经结婚的吗? - 非得结婚才行?
- do it mean they married? - why they got to be married?
Prezbo老师 你干嘛要结婚?
mr. prezbo, why you  even get married?
嗯 理由之一是为了共同营造生活
well, to build a life together, for one--
建立家庭
you know, family.
- 还有拥有亲密关系 - 啥意思啊?
- also to have intimacy. - what do that mean?
就是滚床单呗
mean, like, getting some.
不不 不仅是这些
no no. it's not just that.
亲密可以是 一次安静的谈话
intimacy can be, um, a quiet conversation.
也可以是很有意思的事情 比如
or it can be fun, you know? like
比如给伴侣挠痒痒
when you tickle your partner.
挠我个蛋蛋
yo, tickle my nuts.
好了好了 不说了
all right, all right, no more of that.
行了 先复习考试
come on, let's get to the test material.
下周就州统考了
the statewide exam  is next week.
考完我们再像平时那样上课
and then we'll get back to the regular lessons.
还能跟我们讲亲密关系不?
can we talk about intimacy?
你们想听就行 别弄得我太尴尬
if you like, and if i don't get too embarrassed.
好了...
all right, uh...
账单总额是67.40美元
so, the grand total on the check is $67.40,
但是如果要给小费--
but if they want  to leave a tip--
请看模拟试题
look at your sample test, please.
我说Duquette老师 你们合伙耍我们吧
i got to say, ms. duquette, i feel like y'all schemed us.
这班级跟普通班根本没啥区别
this class is the same as the ones down the hall.
居然还带考试的
yeah, it's 'cause the test's coming up.
好了 大家来看下数学模拟卷
okay, class, let's take a look at the sample math test.
A卷第一题...
in sample "a", we start with...
孩子说得对 这简直是胡扯
kid's right. this is bullshit.
这种考试对他们一点好处都没有
the test material doesn't exactly speak to their world.
对我也没啥好处呐
yeah, don't speak too loud to mine, either.
你估计下 探长
an estimate, detective.
如果撬开那些房门
we start opening those houses,
可能会有好几十具尸体
we might turn over a couple of dozen bodies,
当然这只是我个人估计
but that's just me guessing.
全都是被谋杀的?
all of them homicides?
那小子扫平了半个西区
the boy took over  half the west side.
我们一点没见他用暴力
we never saw the violence.
这些就是板上钉钉的证据
this right here is  the reason why.
你想让我们出动一半的公共警力
you're asking us to call out half of public works
撬开上千所遗弃房屋
and pull the plywood off thousands of vacant houses
好让本市的谋杀率再上升10%?
all so we can raise the city's murder rate by 10%?
我们还在查Stanfield什么?
what else are we doing on stanfield?
我正在设法尽快监听他手下人的电话
i'm trying to get backup on his people's cell phones as fast as i can.
以及调查他的财产
and i started to look for his money.
但若我猜得没错 他们必须绳之以法
but if i'm right about this, they have to be worked.
有证据表明这些失踪人口报告
is there any evidence at all that  links all these missing-persons reports
都与Stanfield组织有关?
to the stanfield organization?
我这还刚开始
i'm just starting at that.
从Fulton街屋子里挖出来的这个是Lex
the one body that we pulled out of the fulton avenue house is lex.
和这案子有直接关系
his case is a direct tie.
另两个失踪人口报告上的名字
and there are two other names on those missing persons reports
曾在年初电话监听中出现过
that show up in our wiretaps from earlier this year.
所以没错 的确有联系 指导员
so, yes, there are  links, counselor.
话说 Landsman跟你们汇报过这事儿么?
by any chance did landsman run this up the chain to you guys?
没有
no.
你决定
your call.
不立案 我的办公室是不会管的
my office won't care until they see case files.
我先报上去看看上头怎么说
i'll run it upstairs and we'll see what comes.
- 好了 我懂了 - 他还脱不开身 不过
- okay, i get it. - he's still tied up, but
真的应该不会太久了
it really should only be a little while longer.
麻烦跟州长说我得回巴尔的摩了行么
can you tell the governor i have to go back to baltimore?
今儿有点小事要处理
i have a little bit of business today.
你爷爷的 我可是美国主要城市市长啊
i'm the mayor of a major american city, for chrissakes.
还得怎么热脸贴他冷屁股?
how much shit do l have to eat from this guy?
换做是你难道不会打官腔么?
wouldn't you play the politics  if you were him?
这事儿州里就没有责任了?
it's not like the state had  no role in this thing.
州里给学校拨的钱也没有监管
you know, the state money for those schools had no oversight either.
我可没跟华盛顿他妈的邮报说
but i'm not telling "the washington" fucking "post,"
他不得不摆脱掉我这个麻烦是因为--
talking about how he might be forced to bail me out because--
原话怎么说来着?
what was the quote again?
"巴尔的摩的孩子也是我的孩子"
because "those are my children in baltimore too."
为了这些钱他能把我剐了
he's gonna bleed me  for that money.
Carcetti市长?
mayor carcetti?
州长办公室来电说州长可以见您了
the governor's office says he's ready to see you now.
5千4百万不是个小数啊
$54 million's a big number.
* 拿不到钱咱就不走 * * 拿不到钱咱就不走--*
* We won't go until we get some, * * We won't go until we get some--*
我做错什么了?
did i do something wrong?
我又没惹是生非
i ain't acted up or nothing.
你该升上去了
you're ready for this.
你能行的
you can do the work.
我相信你
i know you can.
你要是哪天想回来
and if you need to come back here
洗个澡 把脏衣服给我洗
and use the showers or give me laundry,
用用电脑 我这儿随时欢迎
use the computer, you can do that any time.
我来教你吧
anyway, let me show you.
怎样直接从硬盘启动
this here's the way to the hard drive.
没这必要 Duquan
this isn't necessary, duquan.
万一我到时候忙 P老师
just in case i'm busy, mr. p.
你好知道该怎么弄
so you know how to work it.
小子 咋样啊?
hey, boy. what's up?
今天是个大日子 看见没
big day for you. see here?
我把货分成两份儿
i got the inventory divided between us.
你往北大街走...
you gonna go up one way towards north avenue...
我呢沿着高速路的高架往南
and i'm gonna stay down by the highway.
你让我自己收钱找钱?
you gonna let me handle the money alone?
- 你能行吧? - 嗯 行
- you ready, ain't you? - yeah, i'm good.
好 那就上路呗
all right. let's get on it.
晚上回来见
i see you back here tonight.
好嘞
all right.
等等 你要是见到那个狗娘养的 让他把钱拿去 记住了?
hey hey, you see that foul motherfucker, you let him have his money, okay?
你可别跟他对着干
i don't need you messing with him.
- 好 - 那就好
- all right. - all right.
别找错钱
make sure that count's right!
我得找这小杂种谈谈
yo, i need to talk to the little motherfucker.
要不我跟你一块儿去
maybe you can do that with me,
好帮你把把关
see it don't get out of hand.
嘿 Mike!
hey! yo, mike!
怎么啦 Duke?
yo, what up, duke?
我听说Randy的养母也要 把他弄出Tilghman中学了
yeah, i heard randy's foster ma gonna take him out of tilghman too,
送别的地方去
send him somewhere else.
这太扯了吧
that's messed up, man.
行 回见吧
all right, holla, man.
多少?
how many?
理论上说
as a theory,
Freamon探员相信空屋里还有其他尸体
detective freamon believes there could be additional bodies in those vacants,
可能十几具还不止
maybe a dozen or more.
他"相信"
he believes:
Lester Freamon不是那种放空炮的人
lester freamon is not in the habit of selling woof tickets.
我个人至少是不会怀疑他的
i, for one, would not bet against him.
你觉得我该拿这消息怎么办呢?
and what do you suggest i do with this information?
要我说
my feeling is
得把市政厅一起拖下水
that city hall should be brought into the loop.
趁过年前把尸体挖出来
we pull the bodies now before new year's,
统计数据算在Royce的末年任期内
and the stats go to royce's last year in office.
算起明年的犯罪率
matter of fact, it gives carcetti an advantage
Carcetti还能占便宜
with regards to next  year's crime rate.
- 你是说-- - 跟市长说 要拆房就趁今年拆
- you mean-- - tell the mayor that now is the time
别拖到明年
to empty those houses, not next year,
到明年统计数据就要算到他头上了
when it's on his watch and he has to eat the stats.
副总警监啊 我看你算盘打得挺精啊
colonel, i see you've thought this through,
我是说政治上
politically, i mean.
- 现学现卖 - 可不是么
- i'm learning as i go. - i bet you fuckin' are.
副总警监 此次谈话务必保密
colonel, keep this conversation close.
这是直接命令
that's a direct order.
看到Douglass高中那些妞没?
you seen them girls  at douglass, man?
说的没错啊 Duke
yo, you right, duke.
这回跟初中可不一样了
ain't gonna be like middle school no more.
我就是在想啊
you know, i'm just thinking, yo.
不会吧 又来
dag, man, not again.
你们这回住哪儿?
where your people at now?
这堆里有啥要拿的不?
need any of your stuff from the pile?
没啥
it ain't no thing.
兄弟 听我说
yo, man, listen.
我和Bug现在有自己的窝了
me and bug got our own spot now,
你要愿意就来跟我们挤挤好了
so you could come crib with us if you want.
你说Kenard私吞了货什么意思?
what you mean kenard  took the stash?
那你还让他四处溜达?
and he's still walking around?
我会跟他谈的 妈 这事儿不会再有了
i'm gonna talk to him, ma, make sure this never happen again.
看着我 小子
look at me, boy.
Kenard这小子得让他吃点苦头
kenard got to feel some pain for what he did.
- 必须的 - 我不--
- he got to. - i don't--
你不什么 小不要脸的!
you don't what, motherfucker?!
我爱你疼你 你就这么对我?
this how you pay me back for all the love i showed?
干 你还裹着尿布我就让你穿耐克
shit, i been kept you in nikes since you were in diapers.
- 我尽力了  - 尽力了啊?
- i'm trying. - you trying, huh?
下次见着你爹 就准备跟他说你尽力了?
that's what you gonna tell your father the next time you see him, that you trying?
还是打算告诉他你干的好事?
or you gonna tell him what you've done?
他干的好事害他坐牢了--
what he done got him locked up--
没错 你爹进去的时候是条好汉
that's right. wee-bey walked in jessup a man,
出来照样是条好汉
and he gonna walk out one.
你在街上混 顶着他的名 做事却像个娘儿们!
but you out here, wearing his name, acting a bitch!
看看 还知道哭
aw, look at you, crying now.
你他妈往哪儿去?
fuck you think you going?
给我滚回来 老娘我还没讲完呢
get your ass back here. i ain't done talking to you.
我是警察 是吧?
i mean, i'm police, right?
凶杀组的 现在手上有尸体
murder police, and i got bodies.
难道该让他们躺在那儿不成
i'm just supposed to let them laying lie?
"咱不能主动往这火上浇油"
"we don't throw red up on that board voluntarily."
那瘦身版John Goodman的混蛋都说了 (美国肥胖男影星)
that john-goodman-off-his-diet-looking motherfucker was clear on that.
- 陆路不通走水路呗(指跳过Landsman) - 嘿 Jimmy 那是你--
- so go over landsman's head. - mm, jimmy, that's you--
发个匿名传真什么的 Lesters可不是个爱坐船的主
send an anonymous fax. but you see, lester here don't fancy boats.
我嘛 给浴缸放个水我都晕
and me, i get sick  just filling the bathtub.
不得劲儿啊
it's just wrong.
就像詹妮弗·洛佩兹 和那小白脸西班牙男朋友
yeah, just like when i seen j-lo with  that little itty-bitty spanish dude.
天才 把整个社区当成坟场
genius. he hid his mausoleum right in the neighborhood.
那小子哪能满足得了这位大姐
how little pedro gonna fill that big thing up?
唉 这妞的屁股真不是盖的
oh, man, that girl got a prime cut of ass, boy.
- 还有爱心 - 倒挂的爱心吧(还是指屁股）
- and a good heart. - a good inverted heart.
这钉子就是他们的标记
this nail's like their signature.
西区哪扇门上有这钉子
find it in any door  in the west side,
那后头就"板上钉钉"有尸体
and right as rain you're gonna find a body.
是长官 我以追捕Marlo Stanfield为荣
yes, sir. i'm proud to be chasing mr. marlo stanfield.
嘻 弄得跟捉拿Pol Pot似的 (柬埔寨前总理 红色高棉领导人)
man, you act like you on the trail of pol pot or some shit.
谁?
who?
妈的 我赌十块钱我们现在出去
motherfucker, i got $10 says we can leave here right now,
随便找个封起来的空屋子
go to any boarded-up rowhouse
只要门上有这种钉子的
with a nail like that in the door,
就能找到具尸体
and we will find a body.
- 要赌赌20 - 走呗
- make it $20. - there you go.
等等 咱再喝点儿呗 Jimmy你呢?
well, but first let's have another little taste. jimmy, you in?
- 不用 我够了 - 喂 来吧
- no, i'm good. - oh, come on, man.
裙子脱了来喝杯嘛 老天
take that skirt off and have a drink, for chrissakes.
喝你妹
- drink that. - agh!
兄弟 这就没意思了啊
man, don't play like that.
冰棍儿哎 不买要化了
icicles, get 'em before they melt!
卖冰棍
icicles!
冰棍儿 快来买哟
icicles, come get  'em! icicles!
喂 Kenard 你干嘛说谎
hey, yo, kenard. why you lie to me?
你丫胡说什么呢?
fuck you talkin' about?
你说警察踢开你家门进去
you said the police kicked your door in.
我看见那门了 踢过你妹
i seen the door. they ain't kicked shit in.
- 你还打算怎么扯 - 来呀
- how you gonna lie? - go on, man.
- 那一书包货呢? - 书包你妈 傻逼
- yo, where the package at, man? - package up my ass, gump.
- 看我不-- - 看你啥?
- i'm about to-- - you about to?
有种来呀 傻逼二愣子
go on, walk, gump-ass motherfucker.
哎呦
hey, yo,
快看那小兔崽子被人海扁啊
iook at that little dude getting his ass beat!
你他妈跟他罗嗦啥 快去
y'all was talking too goddamn much. go ahead, na'.
让他把书包交出来 咱好闪人
get your pack off this bitch so we can go.
我不想要了
i don't want it.
20块钱拿来 Bunk
i'll take that 20 now, bunk.
这儿黑灯瞎火的看不见
i can't see shit in here.
哎呦
aw, man.
说不定手伸进钱包里
i might pull out my wallet, reach in,
不小心摸出25块什么的
and pull out a $25 by mistake.
我又不会摸钞票上的盲文
i need me some braille bills, something.
你们要给鉴证科打电话么?
you ladies want to call the crime lab?
不打
nah, man.
我喝高啦
i'm like stevie: too high.
不能报告现场
you know i can't do no scene.
上头没说能查 这儿就没有尸体
well, there's not gonna be one, on account of there is no body,
没尸体 哪来的现场
not until the bosses say there is.
没现场嘛 就没得玩喽 小子
and when that happens, you gonna miss all the fun, junior.
你知道Daniels不会让这案子沉了的
you know daniels is gonna keep this alive.
穿白衬衫的都靠不住 你懂的Lester
the white shirts will fuck it up somehow. you know it, lester.
也许这次不会
maybe not, this time.
Daniels是从重案组来的 也许有新气象
daniels is c.i.d. it's a new day downtown.
我来
i got it.
难怪说世界末日了
whew, world is on its hole
居然轮到混小子Jimmy McNulty开车了
when jimmy mcnulty is the most qualified to drive.
是啊 上下不分 黑白不明...
yeah, up is down, black is white...
左右颠倒
ieft is right.
赚了多少哈
what we got here, huh?
- 晚上没啥动静 - 好
- quiet overnight. - cool.
点过名就有人来换你们
relief will be here for  you after roll call.
我是Carver警司
it's sergeant carver.
你怎么样 老弟?
how you doing, dawg?
一晚上没事
quiet overnight.
你今天准备去学校么?
you going to school  this morning?
我看保险起见还是再等等
we're gonna wait a little longer on that to be sure,
可把他扔这我自己去上班也不是个事儿
but i can't say i'm comfortable going to work every day and leaving him here.
将就一星期看看吧
blow over in a week or so, you'll see.
反正我们都派车盯着
till then we still have a car on the house,
有事儿你们随时打我手机
and you have my cell number if anything comes up.
我们会保护好你的
we're gonna look out for you on this.
- 早饭吃了没 警司? - 没呢 我还得--
- have you had breakfast, sergeant? - no, but i gotta--
进来随便吃点不碍事儿
you have time for a plate, i'm sure.
好
sure.
喂
yo,
我梦见个好主意 咱今儿可以试试
i just dreamt something gave me an idea today.
嘿 Sherrod
hey, sherrod.
你记得我们把那个撞倒的电线杆
you remember when we  turned that knocked down
卖了换钱 赚了80块?
iight pole at the scales? pulled $80?
我在想啊不如咱
i been thinking we can
自己去锯倒几根
get to toppling a couple of those bad boys ourselves,
跟鲁班大哥似的 你说呢?
get all paul bunyan and shit, you know?
咱可以小心着干
i mean, we'll be all  discreet and all.
找它条没人的街 锯倒个两三根
not take the hacksaw to no more than a couple on some quiet streets,
留着足够的 好让人取亮儿
leave more than enough for some people to have light and all.
问题是 我今天还有别的事
thing is, i got this other thing i still need to take care of today.
喂 Sherrod 快醒醒
come on, sherrod. wake up.
不早啦
it's late.
不好 你干啥了你 干啥了你?
no no no! what you do? what you do?
你干啥了这是啊?
what you do?
醒醒啊 Sherrod
aw, man, come on, sherrod.
醒醒 别死 醒醒
come on, man. come on. come on.
你不能抽这个呀 孩子
you weren't supposed to do this, man!
老天啊
oh, man!
- 不用电话 - 一个都不用
- no phones: - not a one.
以前还用的那些家伙 --
and the players that were using them before--
Chris Monk Ray-Ray
chris, monk, ray-ray--
都跟街角那儿站着呢
they were out there  on those corners.
没见着有谁拿手机出来的
now i would have seen if someone went to a burner.
他奶奶的!
god damn it!
要是两个月前不撤了监听
if we just stayed up on the wire two months ago,
这点破事儿根本就不会 --
we wouldn't be going  through this sh--
有何贵干
can i help you?
你们哪位是Hauk警司?
which one of you  is sergeant hauk?
- 我 - 我是Shea 这位是Thomas 内部调查的
- i am. - i'm shea. this is thomas. i.i.d.
你是否记得曾从设备科调出一台监控录像机
let me ask if you remember pulling a surveillance camera from l.s.d.,
序列号aw466j9
serial number aw466j9.
有印象吗?
you remember that?
我们还想跟核实下 几个线人的书面报告
we also need to go over your paperwork on a couple of informants,
如果你不介意请跟我们进城一趟
so if you don't mind coming back downtown with us,
你和...
you and...
Sydnor探员 还有一个人
detective sydnor  and the third guy,
叫什么来着 Dozerman
what's his name? dozerman.
Sydnor和Doze都不用找
you don't need sydnor or doze, either.
报告全是我写的 摄像机
paperwork's all mine-- on the camera,
线人 都是我干的
on the informants, me alone.
尸体? 有多少?
bodies? how many?
恐怕不少 具体要等拆了门才知道
could be quite a few. we won't know until we take down those doors.
你们认为是同一毒品团伙干的?
and this is one drug organization you think did this?
只是推论 目前还不能肯定
that's the theory, but nothing's certain at this point.
唯一肯定的是 如果要行动
what is certain is that if we're going to do this,
恐怕事不宜迟
you probably want us to do it now,
赶在新年前
before the new year,
谋杀率的蹿升还能算在Royce市长头上
while the bump in the murder rate is still attributable to mayor royce.
很周到 副局 想得很周到
thoughtful, deputy,  very thoughtful.
我不希望看到你们局再玩数字游戏
i don't want any more stat games from your department.
你得找人进那些屋子里去
you need to get your people into those houses
这仅仅是因为有尸体就得挖出来
because if there are bodies in there, they need to come out.
不过还是现在干吧
but do it now.
一月份我可不想看到什么尸
i don't want to be finding any more bodies come january.
是 先生 市长先生
yes, sir, mr. mayor, sir.
就这么两条路 拿了州里的钱
choice comes down to this:  we take the state money,
不会又烂还又穷
and instead of being fucked up and broke,
咱的学校回到只是烂而已
our schools go back to being merely fucked up.
不用教师裁员 不用取消课程 不用关闭学校
no teacher layoffs, no program cuts, no school closures.
但州长要求他们对校董会有更多控制权
but the price the governor's asking is more state control over the school board
教师工会合同的调整也会让他们能够
and changes in the teachers' union contracts that would allow them
无故取消终身教职
to remove tenured  faculty for cause.
哎呦
ouch.
不拿钱嘛 说起来是对不起孩子
if we don't take the money, it looks  like we're shorting our kids.
拿了钱嘛 是把本地教育监管权拱手让人
we take the money-- we're giving up local control of education,
会让我们失去大部分中产阶级黑人的选票
which is gonna lose us a lot of middleclass black folks.
更别说两年以后你要是去华盛顿特区
not to mention the problem you might have two years from now
拉选票的话 可能遇到的诸多问题
running in the d.c. suburbs,
得解释你如何为了钱 抛弃了学校
explaining how you needed their money to bail out your schools.
他瞧准你要去找他
he sees you coming, tommy.
这个现在不重要
that's not important right now.
拿下吧 我们需要这钱
take the money. we need it.
别看我呀
don't look at me.
你拿了钱 就是出卖了老师们 这归我管
if you take it, you're selling out the teachers, and that's my base.
你不拿钱 是对不起孩子们
if you don't take it, you're selling out the kids.
不管如何 我恐怕都要拿你是问  半个市政厅恐怕也是
either way, i'll probably rip you, and half the council will too.
真庆幸当市长的不是我
just glad i'm not the mayor.
- 你找我? - 上边发话了 开挖
- you called? - word down the chain: open 'em up.
我估计这案子需要更多人手啊
and it's my guess this case is gonna need more manpower.
可不是
yeah, no doubt.
说实话 Herc都要被内务部的人带走了
in fact, i might have lost  herc to an l.i.d. file.
怎么 拦车的事情我已经从轻处理了啊
really? i went light on him for that car stop.
应该连审查组都没去吧
i didn't even think it would get to a trial board.
这事儿恐怕来头更大
this feels like a bigger jacket.
暂时从重案组挑两个人
pick any two you want from c.i.d. for now.
要是你想恢复监听 可以再多加几条线
if you get back up on a wire,  we'll detail a few more.
好极了
beautiful.
不管你怎么说 她太正了
i don't know what you're talking about, but she was hot.
我周五一下班就去
i'm going back on friday  right after work.
等下
hold on.
你他妈瞪什么瞪啊?
what the fuck are you staring at?
你喜欢凶杀组么?
how are you liking homicide?
爱死了 怎么?
loving it. why?
继续说
anyway.
在路上了 老板
it's on the way, boss.
是Joe的信息 不过我们知道怎么回事
it's joe and his message, but we already know what it is.
好了 丫头 走近点
all right, girl. keep it close.
好了 Naldo 给你朋友打电话 游戏开始
all right, 'naldo, call your amigos and tell them it's on.
没错
that's right.
好 就这样
yep. that's it.
好 下盘注意
one, come on. let me  see that footwork.
很好
that's it.
一 二 一 二
one, one, one, one.
对了
that's right.
怎么样 Mike?
yo, what's going on, mike?
兄弟 我觉得我充满力量
man, yo, i feel like i could just pancake
揍个把小毛孩不在话下 你明白吧
a young'un right now, you know what i mean?
你呢 想对练不?
what about you, duke?  want some go?
不 我要跳绳
no, i'ma work this rope.
行 跳你的吧 跟个傻逼似的
yeah, you working it. like a gump.
他们一撤 我们就从两面包抄 明白?
they pull around back, we're gonna come at 'em from both ways, feel me?
给你朋友打电话 告诉他我们在哪儿
hey, yo, call your friends, tell 'em where we at.
- 让我也跳两下吧 - 都说了我在跳了
yo, let me get that rope. i said i'm workin' it.
你他妈就一傻逼
man, i said you's a gump,
臭狗屎 臭屁黑鬼
fucking dogshit and smelling-ass nigger.
喂喂
hey. hey!
我操
man, fuck this.
你走吧 滚!
yeah! go along! get!
这儿没人欢迎你!
don't nobody want you in here, no way!
你看到怎么回事不?
you see what happened?
来了
that be it.
嗨 爹地
hey, daddy.
* Kiss the butt of this lyricist * (Salt N Pepa的Get Up Everybody)
* Blow on my mike and make a wish *
* Get up! everybody, get up *
* Get up! *
给我十块钱爹地 给我十块钱
let me get a $10, daddy.  let me get a $10. i need a $10.
你他妈快给我滚
get the fuck out of here, now.
- 来嘛 15块给您吹箫 - 臭婊子 我说了滚
- come on, i'll suck your dick for $15. - trick-ass bitch, i said get.
要不要看人家那里啊?
don't you want to see my stuff?
呸 谁他妈要看你个臭B
nah, ain't nobody want to see that stink box.
- 快给我滚 - 来嘛 给我十块钱嘛
- get your ass gone. - come on, let me get a $10, player.
搞毛 成旅游景点了?
what the fuck is this, the lnner harbor?
你们都他妈干嘛呢?
yo, what the fuck y'all  think you doing?
- 我们是油漆工 - 是 刷漆来了
- we painters. - si, we paint.
- 把面包车开走 - 保准让你喜欢哟 亲
- move the van out the way. - oh, you gonna like what i got, soldier.
看见没 我们刷油漆
see? we paint. we paint.
好 好
oh... okay.
你们俩谁去把卡车打开?
which one of y'all gonna open the truck for me?
真他妈外行
fucking amateurs.
慢慢喝 孩子
drink it slow, son.
我该怎么办?
what am i gonna do?
我送你回家
i'll run you home.
我不能回家
i-- i can't go home.
她想让我成为我爹 可...
she expect me to be my father, but...
我不是他
i ain't him.
他从前那个样子...
i mean, the way he is and shit...
我真不是这块料
it just ain't in me.
你跟Michael怎么回事?
what's between you and michael?
Mike跟原来不一样了
mike ain't mike no more.
他昨晚对那孩子大打出手
he went hard on this boy last night,
打得鼻青眼肿
fucked his shit up.
我不能回家
i can't go home.
不能回
i can't.
让我们单独聊聊
give us a minute.
我真气我自己
mad at myself, man.
我不该这么把Michael赶出去
i shouldn't have shut  michael out like i did.
Namond是过火了
namond did push it.
他现在可没过火
he ain't pushing nothing now.
看来还得我去当和事老
reckon i'll go mend the fence.
这儿可不是旅馆
this ain't no motel.
执事 你觉得我的人怎么样?
deacon, how'd you get by my people?
你不能把信众转出去 不是这么干的
you can't turn away church folk, ain't done in these parts.
你无事不登三宝殿吧 说吧?
you only come by for a favor, so what is it?
你认识个叫Bunny Colvin的家伙么?
you know a fella named bunny colvin?
嗯 那个流氓警察局指挥官
yeah, that rogue police commander,
鼓吹毒品合法化什么的
tried to legalize drugs.
- 他又想怎么样? - 让他自己说得清楚
- what's he done now? - he can tell you best.
- 你该不会把他-- - 这是好事儿 Odell
- you did not bring-- - it's something positive, odell.
- 跟孩子们有关 - 好事儿 哼?
- has to do with kids. - positive, huh?
Bunny
bunny.
Watkins代表
delegate watkins.
你想要干嘛?
what's this all about?
一个好主意
it's another bright idea.
- 你是Michael Lee的母亲? - 你要抓他还怎么的?
- you michael lee's mother? - he got papers on him or something?
我不是警察
i ain't no kind of police.
- 就是有事想找他聊聊 - 找他的人多了
- i'm just looking to get up with him. - you ain't alone.
他从这儿搬出去 自己找个窝儿
he booked on out of here, got his own spot,
把小弟也带走了
took his little brother with him.
- 你知道他住哪儿么? - 他才不会告诉我呢
- you know where he stay at? - he ain't tell me nothing.
你找找他告诉他一声 家里要他帮忙
you find the boy, you let him know  i need some help around here.
都是老娘撅屁股拉出来的 现在都忘了自己哪儿来的了
i popped him and bug out my ass, and now they forgot where they came from.
你去找她时 我妈怎么说
what my ma say when you called?
她生气了吧?
she was mad, right?
没有
not really.
他妈呀...
his mother...
好个娘们
lovely lady.
她怎么说
what she say?
"让这小子滚回少教所去
"put that bitch in baby  booking where he belongs,
让他好好学学"
iet him learn something."
我还没告诉他我们没要抓他 她就挂断电话了
she hung up before i could tell her we didn't have a charge.
巴尔的摩市911
baltimore city 911.
Pennsie街和Gold街交叉口有人打警察
yeah, they beating a cop over here on pennsie and gold.
- 警察? - 嗯 揍得可厉害了
- police officer? - yeah, they're beating on him bad.
- Pennsylvania和Gold街? - 哟 开枪了都
- pennsylvania and gold? - yo, they firing shots now.
13号 报告有枪击案Pennsylvania和Gold街道
signal 13, report of shots fired, pennsylvania and gold.
13号 --
signal 13--
他们把咱都抢光了啊 Joe
they cleaned the motherfucker out, joe,
全搬进那墨西哥黑鬼开来的面包车
put it in the van them mexican niggers rolled in.
怎么就没人还手呢
i ain't hearing about no resistance.
哪儿来得及啊
man, wasn't no time for that.
Omar带了一整队人马
omar had one of them commando squads with him, man.
有个妞从裤裆里就抽了把枪出来啊 叔
i mean, he had this one ho pulling guns out her pussy, unc.
这哪儿想得到啊
the shit was unseemly, man.
Little先生还真是厉害啊
i got to hand it to mr. little,
- 这事儿还真没想到 - 他们一抢就是整车啊 Joe
- i ain't see this one coming. - they took the shipment, joe.
不是散货 是他妈整车啊
not no package, man, the motherfucking shipment.
我们怎么跟合作的人说啊?
man, what we gonna tell the co-op?
你以为我在想什么呐?
hey, where you think  my mind at right now?
我只知道他妈一大堆土匪等着惹事儿
all i know, it's a lot of gangsters out a lot of shit, man.
咱不如拼一把 找出这个兔儿爷?
i say we mob up and go find this faggot, see?
就该他妈这么办 对这种人不能手软
that's what's really 'hood right there. that's how you deal with shit.
那一屋子的土匪得从我们这儿听说这事
a lotta gangsters in that room need  to take us at our word first.
他们要怀疑 也得先怀疑...
yeah, first thing they gonna wonder about...
咱们
is us.
你来见见我的人吧 我帮你介绍
you need to see my man. i'll hook you up.
这丫是谁?
who is this motherfucker?
我帮你说说去 Mike
let me get a word with you, mike.
听着 你要明白
listen, you got to understand
我这儿不能有肢体冲突
i can't be having no physical confrontation
你之前那样是不行的
iike the one took place back there.
要打出了我健身房打
that kind of thing got  to stay outside my gym.
继续说呀 Montel
yeah. go ahead, montel.
我来是向你道歉的
i come to tell you i was wrong,
我处理得不好
the way i handled it.
滚 黑鬼
step off, nigger.
Mike...
mike...
别碰我
don't touch me, man.
孩子 这儿不是你待的地方
look, man, this here ain't you.
他说了不让你碰他
man don't want you touching on him.
Mike
mike.
我说了 给我滚蛋
i told you, step the fuck off.
小伙子 我在跟你说话呢
young man, if i was talking to you, you'd know i was.
- 操! - 下回就明白了
- shit! - he'll listen next time.
上 做了他
go ahead, man. do him.
别 伙计
nah, man.
我陪你等救护车来吧?
i'll hang here for the ambo, all right?
跟你的人走吧
go with your people.
去吧 孩子
go ahead, son.
烧伤科 闲人免进
authorized personnel only
Johnson医生 请打电话至神经科重症监护
dr. johnson, please call neuro l.c.u.
对不起 孩子
i'm sorry, son.
我会跟社工谈的
i'm gonna talk to social services.
我们会想法帮助你
we'll get you some help.
Randy...
randy...
请值班医生速至神经科重症监护
would the on-call please return to neuro l.c.u.?
值班医生 速回神经科重症监护病房
on-call, please return to neuro l.c.u.
你们会帮忙哈?
you gonna help, huh?
你们会保护我?
you gonna look out for me?
你不是说会保护我吗 Carver警司?
you gonna look out for me, sergeant carver?
你说真的?
do you mean it?
你会照顾好我?
you gonna look out for me?
你保证 保证会罩着我 啊?!
you promise? you got my back, huh?!